Guide to the Michael De Lisio and Irving Drutman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Michael De Lisio and Irving Drutman Papers
1890-2002
1921-2002
YCAL MSS 756
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
34.97
(38 boxes) + 1 record album storage, 19 art
The papers provide insight into the lives and careers of Michael De Lisio, poet and sculptor, and Irving Drutman, a journalist and editor. The papers contain drafts, research notes, and printed versions of De Lisio and Drutman's writings. Correspondence with various authors, artists, and performers, including Peter Bull, Janet Flanner, Lillian Gish, Ira Gershwin, and Lotte Lenya, also sheds light into their professional lives. De Lisio and Drutman's artwork, including De Lisio's sculptures of Ezra Pound and Marianne Moore, and several paintings by Drutman, are part of the papers. De Lisio's career as a sculptor can also be traced in his subject files, exhibition catalogues, and other printed material. Evidence of De Lisio and Drutman's relationship and personal lives can be found in their correspondence, personal papers, and photographs.
De Lisio, Michael
Drutman, Irving
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Sanford Schwartz, 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 20 (videocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 31 (Record Album Storage): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Irving Drutman (1910-1978)
Irving Drutman (1910-1978), American journalist, editor, songwriter, and collector. Born Isidore Druitman to Max Druitman, an upholsterer, and Esther Druitman on July 28, 1910. Drutman wrote articles for the New York Herald Tribune and New York Times. In addition to theatrical journalism, Drutman's involvement in theatre and film also included working as a freelance publicist and songwriting, with songs including "Twilight Song," "Mama Never Told Me," and "Bel Ami." Drutman edited Janet Flanner's memoirs Paris Was Yesterday (1972) and London Was Yesterday (1975), and collected writings Janet Flanner's World (1979). Drutman published his memoir Good Company in 1976. He died of cancer on September 20, 1978 in New York City.
Michael De Lisio (1911-2003)
Michael De Lisio (1911-2003), American poet and sculptor. Born on January 22, 1911 in New York City. De Lisio published poetry in Scribner's and The New Yorker, the latter where he also worked in the office. He served with the navy during the second World War. De Lisio began creating artwork after a two-decade career in public relations for MGM. He exhibited at the Nova Scotia College of Art in Halifax (1969), Minneapolis Institute of Arts (1971), the Brooke Alexander Gallery (1978), the Princeton University Library, Smith College Museum of Art (1974 and 1980), and Boston College (1998). He died in New York City on January 21, 2003.
Scope and Contents
The papers provide insight into the lives and careers of Michael De Lisio, poet and sculptor, and Irving Drutman, a journalist and editor. The papers contain drafts, research notes, and printed versions of De Lisio and Drutman's writings. Correspondence with various authors, artists, and performers, including Peter Bull, Janet Flanner, Lillian Gish, Ira Gershwin, and Lotte Lenya, also sheds light into their professional lives. De Lisio and Drutman's artwork, including De Lisio's sculptures of Ezra Pound and Marianne Moore, and several paintings by Drutman, are part of the papers. De Lisio's career as a sculptor can also be traced in his subject files, exhibition catalogues, and other printed material. Evidence of De Lisio and Drutman's relationship and personal lives can be found in their correspondence, personal papers, and photographs.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series: I. Subject Files, 1932-2000. II. Correspondence, 1928-1999. III. Personal and Professional Papers, 1941-2002. IV. Writings, 1931-1992. V. Other Papers, 1924-1998. VI. Photographs, 1890-1990. VII. Printed Material, 1927-1995. VIII. Artwork, 1938-1965.
American literature -- 20th Century; Art, American -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors, American -- Portraits; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Sculptors -- United States -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Busts (figures) -- United States -- 20th Century; Long-playing records -- United States -- 20th Century; Negatives (photographic) -- United States -- 20th Century; Paintings (visual works) -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographic prints -- United States -- 20th Century; Sculpture (visual work) -- United States -- 20th Century; Videocassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Sculptors -- United States -- 20th Century; LGBTQ resource; Bull, Peter, 1912-1984; De Lisio, Michael; Drutman, Irving; Flanner, Janet, 1892-1978; Gershwin, Ira, 1896-1983; Gish, Lillian, 1893-1993; Lenya, Lotte, 1898-1981; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972 -- Portraits; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972 ( Portraits)
- Subject Files, 1932-2000; Series I; 7.92; (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains material relating to topics of interest to De Lisio and Drutman. The Art Files contains information regarding De Lisio and Drutman's artwork and art collection as well as artists of interest. The last subseries contains files on individuals who De Lisio sculpted. The series also include correspondence relating to Drutman and De Lisio's artwork and collection.
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into three subseries: General, Art Files, and Subjects De Lisio Sculpted.
  - General
    - Abstract Expressionists, undated (Box 1)
    - Acton, Harold, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
    - Algonquin Set, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Art, miscellaneous, 1984-1990 (Box 1)
    - Atkins, Robert, 1996 November 27 (Box 1)
    - Auden, W. H., 1956-1996, undated (Box 1)
    - Avedon, Richard, 1993 October 3 (Box 1)
    - Balanchine, George, 1983-1997 (Box 1)
    - Bankhead, Tallulah, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Barker, Stephen, 1998, undated (Box 1)
    - Baudelaire, Charles, 1991 February 14 (Box 1)
    - Beardsley, Aubrey, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Beach, Sylvia, undated (Box 1)
    - Beck, Bertram, 1965 February 3 (Box 1)
    - Beckett, Samuel, 1967-1995, undated (Box 1)
    - Beckman, Max, 1996 November 28 (Box 1)
    - Benedict, Fabienne, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - Bernhardt, Sarah, undated (Box 1)
    - Berube, Guy, 1994-1998, undated; 5 (Box 1)
    - Behrman, S. N., 1942-1964 (Box 1)
    - Binford, Theron, 1999 June 14 (Box 1)
    - Blewitt, Tom, 1995-1997, undated (Box 1)
    - Bollea, Daniele, 1991-1993, undated (Box 1)
    - Books & Company, undated (Box 1)
    - Boone, Mary, 2000 January 14 (Box 1)
    - Bourke-White, Margaret, 1986 July 20 (Box 1)
    - Brahms, Johannes, 1997 October 5 (Box 1)
    - Brancusi, Constantin, 1995 December 11 (Box 1)
    - Braque, Georges, undated (Box 1)
    - Brinig, Myron, undated (Box 1)
    - Byron, Lord, 1973-1983 (Box 1)
    - Cabot, Edward Ogden, 1994-1995, undated (Box 1)
    - Cadmus, Paul, 1963-2000 (Box 1)
    - Calvino, Italo, 1985 September 29 (Box 1)
    - Caplin, Richard, 1997 February 18 (Box 1)
    - Capote, Truman, circa 1966-1998 (Box 1)
    - Chelsea Hotel, 1983 June 26 (Box 1)
    - Chetham, Charles, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
    - Christo, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Cocteau, Jean, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Colette, 1984, undated (Box 1)
    - Composers, 1987, undated (Box 1)
    - Danaher, Lee, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Davis, George, 1959-1997 (Box 1)
    - De Lisio, Paul, 1997, undated (Box 1)
    - Demuth, Charles, 1969-1975, undated (Box 1)
    - Dickens, Charles, 1987 December 18 (Box 1)
    - Dickinson, Emily, 1983-1986, undated (Box 1)
    - Dinesen, Isak, 1982 November 5 (Box 1)
    - Douglas, Frederick, undated (Box 1)
    - Duchamps, Marcel, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Einstein, Albert, undated (Box 1)
    - Eliot, George, undated (Box 1)
    - Eliot, T. S., 1990, undated (Box 1)
    - Fields, Danny, 1996 July 14 (Box 1)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, undated (Box 1)
    - Flanner, Janet, 1974, undated (Box 1)
    - Flaubert, Gustave, undated (Box 1)
    - Forster, E. M., undated (Box 1)
    - Franceschi, Darko, 1997 February 18 (Box 1)
    - Freud, Lucian, 1994, undated (Box 1)
    - Garbo, Greta, 1987, undated (Box 1)
    - Gaudi, Antonio, 1970-1991 (Box 1)
    - Gershwin, Ira & George, 1988-1998, undated (Box 1)
    - Giacometti, Alberto, 1989-1996 (Box 1)
    - Gill, Brendan, 1970 Jul 16, undated; 2 (Box 2)
    - Ginsberg, Harvey, 1992 December 27 (Box 2)
    - Gish, Lillian, 1968-1997, undated (Box 2)
    - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1986 September 21 (Box 2)
    - Graham, Martha, 1984, undated (Box 2)
    - Graves, Robert, 1983 February 7 (Box 2)
    - Greenberg, Clement, 1992 November (Box 2)
    - Greenfeld, Howard, 1987, undated (Box 2)
    - Griffith, D. W., May 1947 (Box 2)
    - Grosser, Maurice, 1992 September (Box 2)
    - Guggenheim, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Halsman, Phillipe, undated (Box 2)
    - Harris, Ted, 1994-1996 (Box 2)
    - Harris, Theodore, 1996, undated (Box 2)
    - Hart, Kitty Carlisle, 1994, undated (Box 2)
    - Hart, Lorenz, 1995 April 30 (Box 2)
    - Hart, Moss, 1940 October 19 (Box 2)
    - Hellman, Daphne, 1996 August 4 (Box 2)
    - Hellman, Lillian, 1973-1980, undated (Box 2)
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1939, undated (Box 2)
    - Hill, Jerome, undated (Box 2)
    - Hirshorn, Joe, circa 1981 (Box 2)
    - Hopwood, Avery, 1988 February 15 (Box 2)
    - Housman, A. E., 1984 March 15 (Box 2)
    - Isherwood, Christopher, 1964, undated (Box 2)
    - Jaffoni, Joe, 1994, undated (Box 2)
    - James, Henry, 1978-1997, undated; 3 (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Philip, 1998 April 5 (Box 2)
    - Joyce, James, 1982, undated (Box 2)
    - Julien Levy Gallery, undated (Box 2)
    - Kafka, Franz, undated (Box 2)
    - Keats, John, 1984 April 12 (Box 2)
    - Kelly, Richard, circa 1958-1996; 2 (Box 2)
    - Kennedy, Jacqueline, 1996 September 29 (Box 2)
    - Kidd, David, 1996 November 27 (Box 2)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1992-1994 (Box 2)
    - Klee, Paul, 1962-1988 (Box 2)
    - Knapp, Tom, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
    - Dalai Lama, 1988 April 11 (Box 2)
    - Lang, Fritz, 1997 July 20 (Box 2)
    - Lawrence, D. H., undated (Box 2)
    - Lee, Gypsy Rose, 1998 April (Box 2)
    - Léger, Fernand, undated (Box 2)
    - Lerman, Leo, 1994 August 14 (Box 2)
    - Levi, Primo, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Levine, David, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
    - Levitt, Helen, 1999 August 19 (Box 2)
    - Lieberman, Bill, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln, Abraham, 1988, undated (Box 2)
    - Loos, Anita, 1981 August 19 (Box 2)
    - Lord, James, 1996 September 9, undated; 2 (Box 2)
    - Loy, Mina, 1982, undated (Box 2)
    - MacDonald, Dwight, undated (Box 2)
    - Magnani, Anna, undated (Box 2)
    - Malpiedi, Angela, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Manhattan, History of, 1985 September (Box 2)
    - Mann, Erika, 1993 February 18 (Box 2)
    - Mansfield, Katherine, undated (Box 2)
    - Mapplethorpe, Robert, 1988 August 22 (Box 2)
    - Marie-Jeanne, 1996 August 11 (Box 2)
    - Maupassant, Guy de, 1982 April-May (Box 2)
    - Mayhall, Jane, 1998 (Box 2)
    - McAllister, Peggy, 1999 July 2 (Box 2)
    - McBride, Henry, undated (Box 2)
    - McCullers, Carson, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Melville, Herman, undated (Box 2)
    - Mencken, H. L., undated (Box 2)
    - Merrill, James, 1983-1993 (Box 2)
    - Miro, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
    - Mitford, Jessica, undated (Box 2)
    - Modigliani, undated (Box 2)
    - Monk, Julius, 1995 August 22 (Box 2)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1967-1997, undated (Box 2)
    - Moravia, Alberto, undated (Box 2)
    - Moreau, Jeanne, 1994 February 25 (Box 2)
    - Mormando, Franco, 1989-1999 (Box 2)
    - Morris, Dick, 1996 September 8 (Box 2)
    - Murray, Bill, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Nadar, 1977 July 14 (Box 2)
    - Nash, Jeff, 1993, undated (Box 2)
    - Newton, Arvin, undated (Box 2)
    - The New Yorker, undated (Box 2)
    - Nicholson, Johnny, 1995 October 15 (Box 2)
    - Nijinsky, Vaslaw, undated (Box 2)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1996 February 23 (Box 3)
    - Olmsted, Frederick, 1997 January 5 (Box 3)
    - Orwell, Sonia, undated (Box 3)
    - Ossorio, Alfonso, 1997 January 10 (Box 3)
    - Owens, Jeanne, undated (Box 3)
    - Paley, Emily, 1974, undated (Box 3)
    - Parker, Dorothy, 1937, undated (Box 3)
    - Pattison, Pat, undated (Box 3)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1988-1998, undated (Box 3)
    - Pierce, Waldo, undated (Box 3)
    - Pierpont, Claudia, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Pieters, Christine, 1996, undated (Box 3)
    - Powell, Dawn, 1995-1996, undated (Box 3)
    - Proust, Marcel, undated (Box 3)
    - Puccini, Giacomo, 1989 March 12 (Box 3)
    - Purple Prose, 1985 December 15 (Box 3)
    - Ravel, Maurice, 1984 July 1 (Box 3)
    - Redon, Odilon, 1973 May 3 (Box 3)
    - Richardson, Richard, undated (Box 3)
    - Rodin, Auguste, undated (Box 3)
    - Roma, Tom, 1994-1995, undated (Box 3)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., undated (Box 3)
    - Ross, Alvin, 1959-1980, undated (Box 3)
    - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1989 March 12 (Box 3)
    - Rutenburg, Craig, 1992-1998 (Box 3)
    - Sacks, Oliver, undated (Box 3)
    - Saint Gaudens Sculpture Park, 1983 July 24 (Box 3)
    - Sander, Harold, undated (Box 3)
    - Sax, Steve, 1988 November 18 (Box 3)
    - Scaffner, Jon, 1988 March 20 (Box 3)
    - Schapiro, Meyer, 1982 November (Box 3)
    - Schiff, John D., 1969-1973 (Box 3)
    - Schulman, Grace, 1984-1998 (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James, 1997 April 20 (Box 3)
    - Schwartz, Sanford, 2 (Box 3)
    - Severini, Gino, 1995 November 30 (Box 3)
    - Shakespeare, William, 1988, undated (Box 3)
    - Sherman, Hiram, undated (Box 3)
    - Smith, Oliver, undated (Box 3)
    - Solonas, Valerie, 1995 May 29 (Box 3)
    - Sonnenberg, Ben, 1981 September 28; 2 (Box 3)
    - Sovern, Michael, undated (Box 3)
    - Spender, Maro, 1984 December 17 (Box 3)
    - Spender, Stephen, undated (Box 3)
    - Stein, Gertrude, undated (Box 3)
    - Stephanopolous, George, 1996, undated (Box 3)
    - Stevens, Wallace, 1986 October 9 (Box 3)
    - Stevenson, R.L., undated (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Lawrence, 1964-1994, undated; 2 (Box 3)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1980-1982, undated (Box 3)
    - Stravinsky, Igor, 1981 September 30 (Box 3)
    - Strindberg, August, 1984-1987 (Box 3)
    - Svevo, Italo, undated (Box 3)
    - Thomas, Dylan, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1980s; 4 (Box 3)
    - Thurber, James, 1997 February 3 (Box 3)
    - Tintner, Adeline, 1996 December 3 (Box 3)
    - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, 1970-1995 (Box 3)
    - Trevelyan, Raleigh, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Valentino, undated (Box 3)
    - Vidal, Gore, undated (Box 3)
    - Walling, Christopher, 1993-1999, undated (Box 3)
    - Watson, Stephen, 1996-1999, undated; 2 (Box 3)
    - Waugh, Evelyn, 1975-1999 (Box 3)
    - Weill, Kurt, 1995-2001, undated (Box 3)
    - West, Mae, undated (Box 3)
    - Wharton, Edith, 1987 August 23 (Box 3)
    - Whitman, Walt, 1984, undated (Box 3)
    - Wilde, Oscar, undated (Box 3)
    - Williams, Tennessee, circa 1983-1996 (Box 4)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Wittgenstein, Ludwig, undated (Box 4)
    - Wood, Beatrice, 1998 March 14 (Box 4)
    - Woolf, Virginia, 1960s (Box 4)
    - Woollcott, Alexander, 1932-1934, undated (Box 4)
    - Yeats, W. B., 1984 March 18 (Box 4)
    - Zuckerman, Henrietta, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - Art Files
    - Art collection / De Lisio, undated (Box 4)
    - Connoisseur, 1983 January 12 (Box 4)
    - Objets d'Art, 1959-1960, undated (Box 4)
    - Sickert, Walter, 1994 (Box 4)
    - Notes about computer, 1992-1996, undated (Box 4)
    - Sculpture - current, 1989 October (Box 4)
    - Art, Vienna, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Hanover Gallery, 1970 July 27 (Box 4)
    - Zabriskie Gallery, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Publicity / De Lisio, 1958-1970 (Box 4)
    - Documents / De Lisio, 1955-1990 (Box 4)
    - Auctions, miscellaneous, circa 1967-1996 (Box 4)
    - Receipts for Artwork / Drutman, 1961-1975 (Box 4)
    - Nadelman, Elie, 1963-1990, undated (Box 4)
    - Knapp, Tom, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
    - Provenance / De Lisio, 1989, undated (Box 4)
    - De Lisio family, list of relatives, undated (Box 4)
    - Sculpture subjects, 1970-1975 (Box 4)
    - Sculpture ideas, 1985, undated (Box 4)
    - Sculptures, previous price list / De Lisio (empty folder), undated (Box 4)
    - Amherst College (Emily Dickinson), John Lancaster, curator, 1998, undated (Box 4)
    - Sculptures, miscellaneous artists, 1991, undated (Box 4)
    - Addison Gallery of American Art / De Lisio, 1971-1983 (Box 4)
    - Fordham University, 1994, undated (Box 4)
    - Antique objects, receipts, 1958-1965, undated (Box 4)
    - House of El Dieff, Inc., Rare Books and Manuscripts, 1969-1977 (Box 4)
    - Sculptures, "Vintage" notes / De Lisio, 1986, undated (Box 4)
    - Hauswedell & Nolte, 1994, undated (Box 4)
    - Art, estimates, 1966-1976 (Box 4)
    - Auctions and art-sale, 1989-1993 (Box 4)
    - Sculpture, info, 1966-1972, undated (Box 4)
    - Publicity, sculptures / De Lisio, circa 1970-1975 (Box 4)
    - Artwork sold by De Lisio and Drutman, circa 1962-1988; 2 (Box 4)
    - Artists and Writers, undated (Box 4)
    - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, Five self-caricatures and two dogs, 1948-1967 (Box 4)
    - Rouault, Georges, Portrait of Pere Ubu, etching (empty folder), undated (Box 4)
    - Rouault, Georges, Nude dancer, aquatint, undated (Box 4)
    - Gesner, Abelard, Haitian pictures, 1960-1994, undated (Box 5)
    - French painting - Anon (empty folder), undated (Box 5)
    - Beerbohm, Max, caricature by Murray Carson, 1995 June 26 (Box 5)
    - Beerbohm, Max, Sir Reginald Turner, undated (Box 5)
    - Fresnaye, Roger de la, Nude, undated (Box 5)
    - Fresnaye, Roger de la, 1959-1992 (Box 5)
    - Fresnaye, Roger de la, "Jeune Garçon", 1961-1964 (Box 5)
    - Demuth, Charles, "Male in Bath House", 1957-1985, undated (Box 5)
    - Demuth, Charles, "Beach Scene", 1967-1985 (Box 5)
    - Demuth, Charles, "Sailboats", 1958, undated (Box 5)
    - Gershwin, George (Box 5)
    - Hill, Jerome, undated (Box 5)
    - Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig, 1983-1993, undated (Box 5)
    - Modigliani, Amedeo, 1961, undated (Box 5)
    - Pascin, Jules, 1948-1985 (Box 5)
    - Pascin, Jules, Male nude, 1960-1986, undated (Box 5)
    - Rivers, Larry, 1993 December 17 (Box 5)
    - Rivers, Larry, Portrait of Michael De Lisio, 1955-1963 (Box 5)
    - Sculpture, self-promotion / De Lisio, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Salander - O'Reilly Gallery, 1999 December (Box 5)
  - Subjects De Lisio Sculpted
    - "A" General, 1970-1976, undated (Box 6)
    - Anon, undated (Box 6)
    - Auden, W. H., circa 1969-1981 (Box 6)
    - General "B", circa 1968-1977 (Box 6)
    - Baudelaire, Charles, 1977, undated (Box 6)
    - Beach, Sylvia, 1971-1984, undated (Box 6)
    - Beardsley, Aubrey, 1979-1998, undated (Box 6)
    - General "C", circa 1968-1973 (Box 6)
    - Caldwell, Sarah, 1975, undated (Box 6)
    - Capote, Truman, 1984-1985, undated (Box 6)
    - General "D", 1967, undated (Box 6)
    - Demuth, Charles, 1998, undated (Box 6)
    - Dickinson, Emily, 1972-1999, undated (Box 6)
    - General "E", 1968-1979, undated (Box 6)
    - Eliot, T. S., 1971, undated (Box 6)
    - General "F", 1974-1980, undated (Box 6)
    - Fitzgerald, Scott F., 1972-1985, undated (Box 6)
    - Flanner, Janet, circa 1972-1986 (Box 6)
    - General "G", circa 1971-1973 (Box 6)
    - Gide, André, undated (Box 6)
    - Graham, Martha, 1975, undated (Box 6)
    - General "H", 1970s (Box 6)
    - Hartley, Marsden, 1980, undated (Box 6)
    - General "I", undated (Box 6)
    - General "J", 1973, undated (Box 6)
    - James, Henry, 1969-1997, undated (Box 6)
    - Joyce, James, 1972-1980, undated (Box 6)
    - General "K", 1973-1981 (Box 6)
    - General "L", undated (Box 6)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, undated (Box 6)
    - General "M", circa 1968-1970 (Box 6)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1980-1988, undated (Box 7)
    - General "N", 1970-1971, undated (Box 7)
    - Nabokov, Vladimir, 1968-1971, undated (Box 7)
    - General "O", 1968-1972, undated (Box 7)
    - General "P", undated (Box 7)
    - Picasso, Pablo, circa 1967-1981 (Box 7)
    - Poe, Edgar Allan, 1975-1976, undated (Box 7)
    - Pound, Ezra, circa 1970-1976 (Box 7)
    - Proust, Marcel, 1966-1976, undated (Box 7)
    - General "R", undated (Box 7)
    - General "S", circa 1969-1975 (Box 7)
    - Shakespeare & Company, 1981, undated (Box 7)
    - Stein, Gertrude, 1973-1980, undated (Box 7)
    - Stevenson, Robert Louis, 1968-1972, undated (Box 7)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred, undated (Box 7)
    - General "T", 1973, undated (Box 7)
    - Thomson, Virgil, circa 1967-1985 (Box 7)
    - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, 1980-1990, undated (Box 7)
    - General "V", undated (Box 7)
    - Valery, Paul, undated (Box 7)
    - Verlaine-Rimbaud, undated (Box 7)
    - General "W", circa 1967-1980 (Box 7)
    - Waugh, Evelyn, 1983, undated (Box 7)
    - Wilde, Oscar, 1971-1975, undated (Box 7)
    - General "Y", undated (Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1928-1999; Series II; 5.42; (5 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent and subject.
  This series contains De Lisio and Drutman's personal and professional correspondence reflecting their artistic circles. Correspondents include writers, artists, actors, and musicians, such as Peter Bull, Janet Flanner, Ira Gershwin, Lillian Gish, Lotte Lenya, Sonia Orwell, Hiram Sherman, and Raleigh Trevelyan. The series also includes correspondence between De Lisio and Drutman, dating from the 1930s to the 1960s, and which includes postcards illustrated by both De Lisio and Drutman.
  - Auchincloss, Eve, circa 1983-1985 (Box 8)
  - Auden, W. H., 1955-1990; 2 (Box 8)
    Includes newspaper clippings.
  - Baron, Stanley, 1955-1976; 4 (Box 8)
  - Beerbohm, Max, 1964-1974 (Box 8)
    Letters about Max Beerbohm and clippings.
  - Behrman, S. N., 1959-1973 (Box 8)
  - Benedict, Fabienne, 1949-1982; 2 (Box 8)
  - Bernstein, Aline, 1945 October 26 (Box 8)
  - Bianco, Pamela, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Binson, Billy, 1971 March 29 (Box 8)
  - Bird, Isabel and Paul, 1937-1954 (Box 8)
  - Bull, Peter, circa 1969-1990; 2 (Box 8)
  - Cadmus, Paul, 1960s (Box 8)
  - Caplin, Richard, 1985-1987 (Box 8)
  - Chetham, Charles, 1983-1989; 2 (Box 8)
  - Cienfuegos, Antonio, 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Compton-Burnett, Ivy, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Connelly, Ken, 1970s (Box 8)
  - Copland, Aaron, 1959 December 30 (Box 8)
  - Cox, Christopher, 1975, undated (Box 8)
  - Cornell, Katherine, 1966-1968 (Box 8)
  - Crawford, Betty, undated (Box 8)
  - Cunningham, Priscilla, undated (Box 8)
  - David, Gilles, 1975-1977 (Box 8)
  - Davis, George, 1955-1957 (Box 8)
  - Davis, Muriel, 1998-1999, undated (Box 8)
  - Dehn, Paul, 1968-1975 (Box 8)
  - De Lisio, Michael to Irving Drutman, 1930s-1950s; 4 (Box 8)
  - Dietz, Howard, 1946 (Box 8)
  - Draper, Muriel, 1944, undated (Box 8)
  - Draper, Paul, 1942-1944 (Box 8)
  - Drutman, Irving to Michael De Lisio, 1930s-1960s; 11 (Box 8)
  - Drutman, Irving to Michael De Lisio, 1930-1943; 2 (Box 9)
  - Drutman, Julius, 1962 July 1 (Box 9)
  - Dunphy, Jack, 1970s (Box 9)
  - Eichelbaum, Stanley, 1982-1986 (Box 9)
  - Flair Magazine, 1950 (Box 9)
  - Flanner, Janet, 1959-1973, undated; 2 (Box 9)
  - Ford, Hugh, 1981 May 28 (Box 9)
  - Friedman, Samuel, 1960-1962 (Box 9)
  - Gale, Eden, 1993, undated (Box 9)
  - Gannett, Tommy, 1942 December 20 (Box 9)
  - Gershwin, Ira and Leonore, 1963-1983, undated (Box 9)
  - Gish, Lillian, 1967-1993 (Box 9)
  - Glatterman, Al and Ann, 1980-1988 (Box 9)
  - Golde, Morris, 1970s (Box 9)
  - Hamburger, Anna and Philip, 1987 (Box 9)
  - Harkins, Ashton, 1987-1988 (Box 9)
  - Hart, Moss, 1940-1941 (Box 9)